Inventory of the Papers of Daniel J. Meador, 1959-1975
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Papers of Daniel J. Meador 1959-1975
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 82-3
This collection consists of 7 boxes.
This collection consists of Meador's professional papers documenting his scholarship, committee work, and other activities from 1959 to 1975.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
This collection comprises the professional papers of University of Virginia Law professor Daniel J. Meador from 1959 to 1975. A gift from Professor Meador, the papers were accessioned in 1982, and span a broad range of his activities both within and outside the Law School. Meador was active on many faculty committees at the Law School, including the Educational Policy, Appointments and Composition of Student Body. His files contain a large collection of faculty memoranda and minutes, as well as information concerning the library, curriculum, graduate program, grading system, and building of Phase I of North Grounds. Meador's professional activities include scholarly writings, ABA inspection reports, and the Criminal Practice Institute. There is a small amount of correspondence, chiefly concerned with his tenure as Dean of the Law School of the University of Alabama. In addition, there are note cards and files used in preparation for Meador's book cataloging the Library of United States Supreme Court Justice Hugo Black.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1961-1974 (Box 1)
- Faculty Memoranda 1961-1975 (Box 1)
- Law School-Miscellaneous 1961-1975 (Box 1)
- Expense Account Vouchers 1960-1975 (Box 1)
- DOJ Speeches and Testimony of DJM 1977-1979 (Box 1)
- Social Function Invitations 1960-1965 (Box 1)
- Alford/Ritchie Retirement Dinner 1974 (Box 1)
- 5/59 VLR Article: Pupil Assignment 1959-1960 (Box 2)
- 5/59 VLR Article: Reprint Requests 1959-1963 (Box 2)
- VLR Article: Public Schools 1959 (Box 2)
- VLR Article: School Boards 1958-1959 (Box 2)
- 5/59 VLR Article: Little Rock Case Clippings 1959 (Box 2)
- 5/59 VLR Article: Attorneys General 1958-1959 (Box 2)
- ABA Vanderbilt Evaluation Committee 1964-1965 (Box 2)
- ABA Inspections 1957-1965 (Box 2)
- ASIL 1961-1963 (Box 2)
- Southwest Law Teachers Conference 1964 (Box 2)
- CPI: Search and Seizure 1964 (Box 2)
- Academic Review Committee 1972 (Box 3)
- Admissions Committee 1970-1974 (Box 3)
- Appointments Committee 1970 (Box 3)
- Appointments 1970-1971 (Box 3)
- Appointments 1970-1971 (Box 3)
- Appointments 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Appointments 1975 (Box 3)
- Appointments 1974-1975 (Box 3)
- Building Committee 1970-1976 (Box 3)
- Building Committee 1970-1971 (Box 3)
- Building Committee on Furnishings and Decor 1972, 1975 (Box 4)
- Center for Oceans Law and Policy 1976 (Box 4)
- Center for Administrative Justice 1973 (Box 4)
- Center for Advanced Studies 1975 (Box 4)
- Center for Advanced Studies 1974 (Box 4)
- Committee on Composition of Student Body 1973 September-November (Box 4)
- Committee on the Composition of Student Body 1973 April-August (Box 4)
- Final Report, Committee on Composition of Student Body 1974 (Box 4)
- Final Report, Committee on Composition of Student Body 1974 (Box 4)
- Committee on Composition of Student Body n.d. (Box 4)
- Curriculum Committee 1959-1970 (Box 5)
- Dean Search Committee 1969-1976 (Box 5)
- Educational Policy Committee 1971 (Box 5)
- Educational Policy Committee 1972 (Box 5)
- Educational Policy Committee 1973 (Box 5)
- Educational Policy Committee 1974-1976 (Box 5)
- Faculty Minutes 1958-1961 (Box 6)
- Grading System 1958-1973 (Box 6)
- Graduate Program 1958-1973 (Box 6)
- Joint Degree Program 1971-1975 (Box 6)
- Latin American Seminar 1959-1961 (Box 6)
- Law Alumni 1959-1974 (Box 6)
- Law School Foundation 1965 (Box 6)
- Law School Self-Study 1974 (Box 6)
- Legal Methods Course 1961-1965 (Box 6)
- Legislation Course 1958 (Box 6)
- Law Library Committee 1960-1964 (Box 7)
- Law Library Committee 1965-1976 (Box 7)
- Law Librarian Search Committee 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Moot Court Board 1973-1976 (Box 7)
- Part Time Students 1973-1976 (Box 7)
- Long Range Planning 1975 (Box 7)
- Pictures 1974 (Box 7)
- Public Occasion Committee 1976 (Box 7)
- Committee on Size of Law School 1964-1973 (Box 7)
- University Self-Study 1964 (Box 7)
- University Self Study 1964 (Box 7)
- Virginia Law Review 1959-1960 (Box 7)